你好，你们这些漂亮的人。
Hello you beautiful people.
现在，吸引您使用Linux的一个关键因素可能是开源软件的想法。
Now one key thing that probably brought you to work with Linux is the idea of open source software.
但是这个词到底是什么意思呢。
But what does that term really mean.
在这段视频中，我们将讨论新项目以及它对软件的实际意义
Well in this video we're going to talk about the new project and what it actually means for software
开放源码和整个开放源码运动的历史。
to be open source and the history of the whole open source movement.
所以，让我们继续下去，开始吧。
So let's go ahead and get into it.
好的。
OK.
因此，我们可能首先需要了解的是，当我们听到这个词时，Linux实际上是什么
So the first thing that we probably need to understand is what Linux actually is when we hear the word
我们可能会认为我们使用的整个操作系统就是Linux操作系统。
Linux we probably think of a whole operating system that we use as being the Linux operating system.
现在，令人惊讶的是，事实并非如此，Linux实际上只是整个体系中的一部分
Now surprisingly this is actually not the case and Linux is actually just one of the pieces of the whole
操作系统是内核。
operating system the kernel.
所以让我解释一下。
So let me explain.
9月1日1983年9月，一个叫理查德·斯托尔曼的人宣布，他将开始
On Sept. 27 the September in 1983 a person called Richard Stallman announced that he was going to begin
开发一个类似于Unix操作系统但完全免费的操作系统
developing a operating system that was similar to the Unix operating system but made of entirely free
软件。
software.
现在这个操作系统被称为新的操作系统，拼写为g和U，它代表Ganu is
Now the operating system was called the new operating system spelled g and U which stands for Ganu is
而不是他们喜欢称之为递归缩写的Unix。
not Unix which they like to call a recursive acronym.
好的。
OK.
1984年1月，理查德·斯托尔曼(Richard Stallman)辞去了人工智能实验室(AI Lab)的工作
Now in nine in January 1984 Richard Stallman quit his job in the Artificial Intelligence Lab at the
麻省理工学院让麻省理工学院全职致力于GANU项目的目标是创造
Massachusetts Institute of Technology so MIT to work on the Ganu project full time in the aims of creating
由完全自由的软件组成的操作系统。
an operating system made of completely free software.
现在，术语自由软件实际上指的是软件给予用户的几个自由，而不是
Now the term free software actually refers to several freedoms that the software gives the user rather
而不是像金钱一样自由。
than being free as in money.
因此，当你听到“自由软件”这个词时，想想言论自由，而不是免费午餐。
So when you hear the term free software think free speech and not free lunch.
现在，这些自由是第一次。
Now these freedoms are the first.
第一个是出于任何目的随心所欲地运行程序的自由。
First one is the freedom to run the program as you wish for any purpose.
第一个自由，第二个自由是研究程序如何工作并对其进行更改的自由
The first freedom the second freedom is the freedom to study how the program works and change it so
它可以按照你的意愿进行计算。
that it does the computing as you wish.
这就是一个人的自由。
Which is what freedom one is.
好的，自由一是程序会做你想做的事。
OK freedom one is that the program will do what you wish.
对我来说，自由就是研究程序是如何工作的自由，并对其进行更改，使其按照您的方式运行
Freedom to me is the freedom to study how the program works and to change it so that it does as you
祝愿。
wish.
现在，访问程序的源代码是实现这一点的前提条件。
Now access to the source code for a program is a precondition for this.
你不能研究一个程序是如何工作的，你可以看它的代码。
You can't study how a program works and you can look at its code.
因此，能够访问源代码是自由号的前提条件。
So having access to the source code is a precondition for freedom number.
第三个自由是重新分发软件副本的自由，这样您就可以像他们说的那样
The third freedom is the freedom to redistribute copies of the software so that you can as they say
帮助您的邻居，而不是以前的自由是分发修改版本的副本的自由
help your neighbor and freedom not before is the freedom to distribute copies of your modified version
你的软件。
of your software.
如果你修改它，你可以将这个愿望重新分配给帮助他人的自由3号。
If you modify it you can redistribute that Wishings to freedom number 3 of helping other people.
而是由和。
But by and.
显然，通过这样做，您可以让整个社区有机会从您的更改中受益。
Apparently by doing this you can give the whole community a chance to benefit from your changes.
同样，访问源代码是实现这一点的前提条件。
And again access to the source code is a precondition for this.
好的，所以如果您想修改软件并重新分发它，您需要有权访问源代码
OK so if you want to modify software and redistribute it you need to have access to the source code
以便能够改变它。
in order to be able to change it.
现在有了一个许可证，它合法地向软件用户提供这些自由，被称为
Now there's a license that legally provides a user of software with these freedoms and is known as the
皮划艇公共执照或GPL。
canoe public license or the GPL.
现在有多个版本的Gonu公共许可证或GPL，但在录制GPL时
Now are several versions of the Gonu public license or the GPL but at the time of recording the GPL
版本3是最现代的版本。
version 3 is the most modern version.
但是在1991年，新的系统几乎完工，但是新的操作仍然缺少一个部分。
But in 1991 the new system was almost finished but there was still one part missing from the new operating
这是一个重要的组成部分。
system and it was an important part.
这最后一个部分是每个操作系统的主要部分，它被称为内核。
This final piece is a major part of every operating system and it's called the kernel.
内核负责分配计算机硬件上的资源，这些资源由
The kernel is responsible for allocating the resources on the computer's hardware that is required by
正在运行的软件，因此它是计算机硬件和应用程序之间的接口层
the software that is running so it's the interface layer between the computers hardware and the applications
它正在运行。
that it's running.
好的，1991年的这个时候，一个叫莱纳斯·托瓦尔兹的人正在大学完成他的MFC论文
OK now at this time in 1991 a man called like Linus Torvalds was completing his MFC thesis at the University
作为这项工作的一部分，Lenas发明了一个类似Unix的内核，称为Linux，它
of Helsinki in Finland and as part of this work Lenas invented a Unix like kernel called Linux and it
以他自己的名字命名为Linux。
was called Linux after his own name.
但是Unix世界中的所有东西都是以X结尾的。
But everything in the Unix world kind of ends in an X..
所以Linux在下一步就结束了。
So Linux ending in the next.
Linux可以吗？
Is Linux OK.
在一位同学邀请维特去看理查德·斯托尔曼的演讲后，
And after being VEIDT after being invited by a fellow student to go see a talk by Richard Stallman who
在Lenas发布linux内核的第2版时，他也是一位著名的活动家。
is also a prominent activist at the time Lenas released the Linux kernel under the version 2 of the
新的公共许可证或GPL，从而使Linux内核成为免费软件，因此Fang对Linux内核来说也是如此
new Public License or GPL thereby making the Linux kernel free software so Fang's to the Linux kernel
新的操作系统是完整的，并且是完全可运行的操作系统，由完全免费的
the new operating system was complete and and was fully runnable operating system made of entirely free
软件。
software.
有了我们之前谈到的这四个自由，它开始流行起来，实际上是Linux
With those four freedoms we talked about before and it began to gain popularity and it in fact the Linux
今天在Android设备甚至Chrome OS上使用的内核，所以如果你曾经听到人们说哦
kernel that is used today on on Android devices and even Chrome OS so if you ever hear people say oh
Android运行Linux或Chrome OS运行Linux，他们的意思是使用Linux内核进行接口
Android runs Linux or Chrome OS runs Linux what they mean is they use the Linux kernel to interface
位于计算机的软件层和硬件层之间。
between the software layer and the hardware layer of your computer.
但是因为linux内核是最后一块，所以它得到了很大的关注，睡觉
But because the Linux kernel was the final piece it kind of got a whole lot of attention and the rest
在新的操作系统中所做的工作都被遗忘了。
of the work that went into the new operating system was kind of forgotten.
而是因为当我们运行像Buntu或任何其他Linux发行版这样的发行版时，我们运行的实际上是
But because what we run when we run a distribution like a buntu or any other Linux distribution is actually
新的操作系统和Linux内核。
the new operating system and the Linux kernel.
有人建议，为了给团队项目以信任，而不是仅仅给整个项目打电话
It was recommended that in order to give the group project its credit instead of just calling the whole
Linux的东西，我们应该叫它新的。
thing Linux we should call it new.
加上Linux。
Plus Linux.
事实上，有一个名为you name命令的命令，它实际上会告诉您大量的信息
In fact there is a command called the you name command that will actually tell you loads of information
关于您的计算机的信息，例如它有什么硬件，它正在运行什么操作系统。
about your computer such as what hardware it has and what operating system that it's running.
因此，如果您使用o选项在命令中运行该单元，它将告诉您您的操作系统。
So if you run the unit in command with the o option it'll tell you your operating systems.
如果我们运行它，我们可以看到我们可以获得GANU劈开LINUX作为操作系统。
If we run that we see that we can we get Ganu slash Linux as the operating system.
听起来很酷，对吧。
Sounds pretty cool right.
好的，了解了历史之后，我们现在知道了到目前为止您在
OK so with that history understood we now know pretty much all of the commands of you so far in the
课程(如ls命令、find命令等)都是新项目的一部分，并给出
course such as the ls command of the find command and so on are all part of the new project and to give
用户可以享受自由软件提供的自由。
the users the freedoms that free software provides.
源代码需要可供阅读，因为访问源代码是以下各项的前提条件
The source code needs to be available to read because access to the source code is a precondition for
这些自由是对的。
those freedoms right.
因此，换句话说，该软件必须是开源的。
So in other words the software must be open source.
好的，所以源代码必须是开放的，才能访问。
Ok so the source code must be open be accessible.
它是开源的。
It's open source.
那么，为什么我们要看一下我们的计算机运行的代码。
So how come we have a look at the code that our computer runs.
实际上，在独木舟项目的官方网站Ganu.com org上都可以免费访问。
Well it's actually all freely accessible on the canoe project's official Web site Ganu dot org.
所以，如果我在这里打开一个Firefox浏览器，当它启动后，我们就转到新的.org。
So if I just open up a Firefox browser here and when that boots up we head over to the new dot org.
我们可以看到我在说什么，所以我们就在这里。
We'll be able to see what I'm talking about so here we are.
有Firefox。
Has Firefox.
让我们转到Ganu dot org并按Enter键。
Let's go to Ganu dot org and press enter.
我们走吧。
There we go.
所以你可以更详细地阅读自由软件思想背后的哲学，你可以
So you can read all about the philosophy behind the Free Software ideology in more detail and you can
看这里，它在告诉您在这里尝试新的Linux。
see here it's telling you to try new Linux here.
但是如果您转到软件部分，如果我们单击此处的软件并向下滚动到某个部件
But if you head over to the software section if we click on software here and scroll down to a part
上面写着都是好的新包裹。
that says all good new packages.
这里写着组织新包裹。
Here it says org new packages.
您可以在这里看到，这里基本上链接到运行在其上的每一段代码
You can you can see here that there's every This basically links to every bit of code that is run on
一个包含Linux内核本身的自由软件版本的新系统，我们可以在
a new system including a free software version of the Linux kernel itself which we can find under the
Linux lb.软件包显示我们是Linux 1b..
Linux lb. package say we are Linux lb..
好的，这就是软件包，这是包含所有源代码的完整可下载文件夹
OK that's the that's the package that's the full downloadable folder that contains all of the source
Linux内核本身的V代码。
code for V for the Linux kernel itself.
这真是太棒了。
That's pretty awesome.
现在，对于您到目前为止已经运行的所有命令，这是ls命令grep find，不管它是什么。
Now for all the commands that you've run so far this is the ls command grep find whatever it might be.
好的。
OK.
您可以在核心utils包下找到它们，我们会叫您Tell。
You can find those under the core utils package that we'll call you tell.
好的。
OK.
所以你可以在那里找到你告诉我们的电话包裹里的东西。
So that's where you can find the stuff in there in that call you tell us package.
在下一个视频中，我们将下载call utos包，对其进行修改并安装新版本
And in the next video we're going to download the call utos package modify it and install a new version
将ls命令发送到我们的计算机，这将是非常令人兴奋的。
of the ls command to our computer which is going to be super super exciting.
但首先让我们快速回顾一下我们在这段视频中学到了什么。
But first let's just take a quick recap of what we've learned in this video.
好的。
OK.
在这段视频中，您了解到Richard Stallman开始开发新的操作系统
So in this video you learned about Richard Stallman beginning the development of the new operating system
在1983年，当时的想法是创建一个完全由自由软件组成的类似Unix的操作系统。
in 1983 and the idea was to create a Unix like operating system that was made of entirely free software.
你会发现，当我们说自由软件时，我们指的是为用户提供特定功能的软件
And you learn that when we say the words free software we mean software that provides users with certain
自由所以想想言论自由，而不是免费午餐。
freedoms so think of free speech rather than free lunch.
好的。
OK.
第四，自由软件给了用户四种自由
Now the Fourth there are four freedoms that the free the free software gives the users so gives the
用户可以出于任何目的随心所欲地运行程序。
users the ability to run programs as they wish for any purpose.
它使用户能够研究程序是如何工作的，并将其更改为
It gives the users the ability to study how a program works and change it so it does the computing as
他们希望并且能够访问源代码是实现这一目标的前提条件，它使用户能够
they wish and access to source code is a precondition for that and it gives the users the ability to
免费分发他们得到的任何副本，这样他们就可以帮助其他人。
freely freely distribute any copies they get so that they can help other people.
它还使用户能够分发他们创建的软件的修改版本
And it also gives the users the ability to distribute modified versions of the software that they create
其他人。
other people.
因此，这允许整个社区从用户所做的任何更改中受益。
So this allows the whole community to benefit from any changes that a user makes.
同样，访问源代码也是实现这一目标的前提条件。
And again access to source code is a precondition for that as well.
现在，这些自由被合法地提供给使用新的公共许可证或GPL的用户。
Now these freedoms are legally provided to users using the new Public License or the GPL.
正如我录制GPL的时候一样，GPL的第三版GPL版本3是最现代的
And as I as the time of recording the the third version of the GPL GPL version 3 is the most modern
许可版本和开放获取源代码是给予这些自由的前提条件。
version of the license and open access to the source code is a precondition for giving these freedoms.
因此，当拥有可公开访问源代码的软件时，它被称为开源软件，这样您就可以
So when have software has openly accessible source code it is known as open source software so you can
说自由软件是开放源码的，但并不是所有的软件或不是所有的开放源码软件都是自由软件
say that free software is open source but not all soft or not all open source software is free software
因为虽然人们可能会让你看到源代码，但这并不意味着他们一定会给你
because while people might let you see the source code that doesn't mean they necessarily give you the
修改和分发它所需的自由。
freedoms required to modify and distribute it.
他们可能只会让你看到源代码，但是自由软件确实需要开源软件
They might just let you see the source code OK but the free software does does require open source software
因此，它以一种方式工作，而不是以另一种方式工作。
so it works one way but not the other.
你们也已经了解到，1991年，新项目几乎完工，但它有一个重要的缺失
And you've also learned that in 1991 the new project was almost finished but it had a important missing
它是内核，内核是操作系统的一部分。
piece which was the kernel and the kernel is the part of the operating system.
硬件和之间的接口根据软件从硬件分配资源
The interfaces between the hardware and allocates resources from the hardware depending upon what software
需要它。
requires it.
1991年，Linus Torvalds创建了他自己的内核版本，并将其命名为Linux内核并发布
And in 1991 Linus Torvalds created his own version of a kernel and called it the Linux kernel and released
1991年，它也在新的公共许可证版本下运行，从而使其成为自由软件。
it in 1991 under the new Public License version too thereby making it free software.
所以Linux内核是新操作系统的最后一块，现在两者倾向于协同工作。
So the Linux kernel was the final piece for the new operating system and now the two tend to work together.
因此，当您下载Buntu或下载任何其他类型的Linux发行版时，您实际上
So when you download a buntu or when you download any other type of Linux distribution what you're actually
下载是新的Plus Linux操作系统的一个版本。
downloading is a version of the new Plus Linux operating system.
因此，从今以后，我们不再只称它为Linux，我们将称它为新的Linux操作系统。
So henceforth we won't just call it Linux we'll call it the new Linux operating system.
好了，在接下来的视频中，既然我们理解了我们所理解的这一小段历史课程
OK so in the next video now that we understand this little bit of a history lesson we understand about
自由和开放源码软件的全部内容。
the freedoms and what open source software is all about.
我们将使用一些源代码。
We're going to play with some source code.
好的，我们将下载并查看一些核心命令的源代码。
OK we're going to download and take a look at some of the source code for some core commands.
修改他们的代码，并在我们的计算机上安装修改后的代码，看看他们的行为有何不同。
Modify their code and install that modified code on our computer and see how they behave differently.
所以这将是令人惊叹的，它将真正让你看到哪些开放源码的自由软件
So it's going to be amazing and it's going to really allow you to see what open source free software
都是关于。
is all about.
好了，我会在下一个视频中见到你。
So for all that goodness I'll see you in the next video.